<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thacher Shields</title>
    <link>https://thacher.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thacher Shields</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:46:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thacher.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Hugo Site to cPanel</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-cpanel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:46:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-cpanel/</guid>
      <description>This website is built using a technology called Hugo. Hugo is brilliant because you can write as little or as much html, css, and js as you want. Written in Go, Hugo is a lightweight and immensely fast content management system. Think Wordpress, but using Markdown instead of PHP. Well I love it and I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to using it for my personal site. Now that I have a few weeks&amp;rsquo; experience under my belt, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get serious about deployment and organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 21:50:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Thacher. Like Becky or Margaret. I&amp;rsquo;m a UX designer in NC and I&amp;rsquo;m mildly obsessed with learning new things. As a UX designer, I strive to make complicated tasks easy and delightful. I take great pleasure in figuring out new ways to do things and having fun in the process. Having worked in a lot of industries, UX is the only one that&amp;rsquo;s really gotten me out of bed in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClassMate</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/classmate/classmate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/classmate/classmate/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing Hybrid Learning
Thacher Shields | Nick DeBakey | Danait Teklemariam | Vianca Barlis
Design Challenge The design challenge we have selected is the Burson Hall physical/virtual hybrid classroom renovation. We have developed two design goals to improve upon the current structure that will guide the renovation process. In addition, we aim to improve the collaboration process between virtual and in-person students by increasing interaction capabilities across in-person and remote students and mitigating common privacy concerns.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
