<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thacher Shields</title>
    <link>https://thacher.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thacher Shields</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 14:43:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thacher.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design Project - Sharing Expenses with your Partner</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/settleup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 14:43:28 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/settleup/</guid>
      <description>This is a design project that I lead during my time in customer insight and innovation. Our initial project statement was, &amp;ldquo;what can we do to support couples before, during, and after their wedding?&amp;rdquo; After our first round of research, we discovered that most couples already have a pretty good handle on their wedding preparation and execution. We did, however, learn that most couples had interesting and surprising strategies for paying for their event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing Back on Product Partners</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/posts/working-with-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:40:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/posts/working-with-product/</guid>
      <description>In my two years in the enterprise UX space, I&amp;rsquo;ve gained a number of soft skills that they didn&amp;rsquo;t prepare me for in college. At no point in my undergrad or masters programs did my instructors tell me that I&amp;rsquo;d have to tell people no. Learning that lesson took real on-the-job experience. Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about the relationship between product managers and UX designers.
The Relationship During my time as a Senior User Experience Designer, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked closely with several key stakeholders for each of my projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Negotiation App</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 12:17:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/negotiate/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of buying secondhand premium items on sites like Facebook Marketplace and Craigslist. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve scored some pretty incredible deals. In 2021, I snagged a pair of new-in-box 1970 JBL L100 loudspeakers for $25. That might be the best deal I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten. But enough about the happy parts of the process. What about the negatives?
Problem Statement Negotiating on digital marketplaces typically follows a consistent pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart TV Remotes</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/smart-remotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:35:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/smart-remotes/</guid>
      <description>According to a 2023 study by Hub Research, 74% of TV households have a smart TV. Statista says there are 125 million TV households in the United stats. That means that nearly 93 million American homes have smart TVs. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of smart TVs. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say that the smart TV has kind of become an integral part of the modern American home. And I think the en masse move to the smart TV makes a lot of sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Hugo Site to cPanel</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-cpanel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 12:46:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-cpanel/</guid>
      <description>This website is built using a technology called Hugo. Hugo is brilliant because you can write as little or as much html, css, and js as you want. Written in Go, Hugo is a lightweight and immensely fast static site generator. Think Wordpress, but using Markdown instead of PHP. Well I love it and I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to using it for my personal site. Now that I have a few weeks&amp;rsquo; experience under my belt, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get serious about deployment and organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 21:50:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Thacher. I&amp;rsquo;m a Senior User Experience Designer in North Carolina and I&amp;rsquo;m hooked on learning new things. Like this website, for example. I built it using Hugo and I&amp;rsquo;m still working out the kinks (pardon our dust). As a Senior UX Designer, I strive to make complicated tasks intuitive and delightful. I take great pleasure in figuring out new ways to do things and making it fun to do them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClassMate</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/classmate/classmate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/classmate/classmate/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing Hybrid Learning
Thacher Shields | Nick DeBakey | Danait Teklemariam | Vianca Barlis
Design Challenge The design challenge we have selected is the Burson Hall physical/virtual hybrid classroom renovation. We have developed two design goals to improve upon the current structure that will guide the renovation process. In addition, we aim to improve the collaboration process between virtual and in-person students by increasing interaction capabilities across in-person and remote students and mitigating common privacy concerns.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
