<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on Thacher Shields</title>
    <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on Thacher Shields</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 12:17:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thacher.me/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Negotiation App</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 12:17:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/negotiate/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of buying secondhand premium items on sites like Facebook Marketplace and Craigslist. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve scored some pretty incredible deals. In 2021, I snagged a pair of new-in-box 1970 JBL L100 loudspeakers for $25. That might be the best deal I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten. But enough about the happy parts of the process. What about the negatives?
Problem Statement Negotiating on digital marketplaces typically follows a consistent pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart TV Remotes</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/smart-remotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 14:35:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/smart-remotes/</guid>
      <description>According to a 2023 study by Hub Research, 74% of TV households have a smart TV. Statista says there are 125 million TV households in the United stats. That means that nearly 93 million American homes have smart TVs. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of smart TVs. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say that the smart TV has kind of become an integral part of the modern American home. And I think the en masse move to the smart TV makes a lot of sense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClassMate</title>
      <link>https://thacher.me/portfolio/classmate/classmate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thacher.me/portfolio/classmate/classmate/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing Hybrid Learning
Thacher Shields | Nick DeBakey | Danait Teklemariam | Vianca Barlis
Design Challenge The design challenge we have selected is the Burson Hall physical/virtual hybrid classroom renovation. We have developed two design goals to improve upon the current structure that will guide the renovation process. In addition, we aim to improve the collaboration process between virtual and in-person students by increasing interaction capabilities across in-person and remote students and mitigating common privacy concerns.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
