<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Thacher Shields</title>
        <link>https://thacher.me/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Thacher Shields</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 23:04:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thacher.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>The Best Rum</title>
            <link>https://thacher.me/posts/the-best-rum/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 23:04:39 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://thacher.me/posts/the-best-rum/</guid>
            <description>Today, I got a text from my dad:
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the best rum&amp;rdquo;
My immediate thought was, &amp;ldquo;idk, Appleton 50 year?&amp;rdquo; I guess that&amp;rsquo;s the most expensive rum. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly helpful though, so I started a dialogue.
&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a complicated question with a complicated answer.&amp;rdquo;
He further refined his question.
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the best rum to make silly cocktails with?&amp;rdquo;
Come on now. They&amp;rsquo;re not silly. They have flair. But seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s a bad question.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I got a text from my dad:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;What&rsquo;s the best rum&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My immediate thought was, &ldquo;<em>idk, Appleton 50 year?</em>&rdquo; I guess that&rsquo;s the most <em>expensive</em> rum. That wasn&rsquo;t particularly helpful though, so I started a dialogue.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s a complicated question with a complicated answer.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He further refined his question.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;What&rsquo;s the best rum to make silly cocktails with?&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Come on now. They&rsquo;re not silly. They have <em>flair</em>. But seriously, it&rsquo;s a bad question. A better question is, &ldquo;What is the most versatile rum?&rdquo; And I think we can work with that. I&rsquo;ll even refine the question a little further than that.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you could only have one rum behind your bar, what would it be?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In our hunt for the one rum everyone should keep on hand, we must first start by describing rum. How can we categorize it? A novice may categorize rum like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Light Rum</li>
<li>Gold Rum</li>
<li>Dark Rum</li>
</ul>
<p>If you&rsquo;re making rum and cokes, frozen piña coladas, and the occasional rum ham, you can totally get away with this system. Bacardi uses this system. Why shouldn&rsquo;t you? Here&rsquo;s the thing - Bacardi thinks you&rsquo;re stupid. Color isn&rsquo;t a great way to describe the flavor of rum. Typically, a spirit takes on color as it is aged in wood. The trouble with this system, however, is that there aren&rsquo;t any consistent rules surrounding the distillation of rum. Rum comes from a lot of places and every country has their own rules about how you can describe and advertise your spirit. This can lead to a lot of ambiguity about the characteristics of a given rum based on the color, name, and descriptors. Let&rsquo;s explore a better system - heritage. Rum has three main heritages:</p>
<ul>
<li>British</li>
<li>Spanish</li>
<li>French</li>
</ul>
<p>British style rum comes from Barbados (Plantation, Mount Gay, Real McCoy), Guyana (El Dorado, Lemon Hart, Hamilton), and Jamaica (Appleton, Smith &amp; Cross, Meyers, Wray &amp; Nephew). British style rums are made from molasses and tend to be bold, rich, and complex.</p>
<p>From Spain, there&rsquo;s Cuba (Havana Club), Puerto Rico (Don Q, Bacardi), and the Dominican Republic (Kirk &amp; Sweeney, Brugal, Barcelo). Spanish style rums are also made from molasses, but tend to be much lighter. They are smooth and buttery by contrast.</p>
<p>Finally, from France, we have Martinique (Rhum Agricole) and Haiti (Barbancourt). French style rum is almost an entirely different spirit. Being made from pressed sugarcane juice, it carries an entirely different flavor. French style rums are earthy, herbal, and vegetal by contrast. I actually struggle to even call rum of French origin &ldquo;rum.&rdquo; The term &ldquo;Rhum Agricole&rdquo; helps differentiate French style rums from the reset of the flock.</p>
<p>Now let&rsquo;s get <em>obnoxiously technical</em>. In his book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Smugglers-Cove-Exotic-Cocktails-Cult/dp/1607747324">Smuggler&rsquo;s Cove</a>, Martin Cate says there are three things to look for when categorizing rum:</p>
<ol>
<li>Material</li>
<li>Still</li>
<li>Age</li>
</ol>
<p>There are two kinds of materials that are distilled to make rum - molasses and pressed sugarcane. Typically, rum is made from molasses. If you see a rum in the store, that&rsquo;s like what it was made from. Rum that is made from pressed sugarcane, on the other hand, is called Rhum Agricole. As we discussed earlier, Rhum Agricole comes from French countries and is much more grassy and earthy than rum made from molasses.</p>
<p>The second factor is the kind of still used to make the rum. Rum is usually distilled in a pot still or a column still. Pot still rums have a bolder flavor and pack a punch. Column still rums are smoother, lighter, and more refined. Of course, you can always blend the two distillates to get the best of both worlds.</p>
<p>Lastly, there&rsquo;s the age of the rum. When a rum is aged (typically in wooden barrels), it mellows out. It gets smoother. Aged rums tend to have a deeper and more complex flavor than young rums. Young rums, however, often retain more of that punch. <em>Typically</em>, you can tell if a rum is aged based on what color it is. That&rsquo;s not always true though because there are no rules about adding caramel color to your product. Kraken, for example, is only aged 1-2 years, but appears very dark in color. That color comes from caramel coloring additives rather than wood aging.</p>
<p>So what does all of this mean? How do you decipher what a rum will taste like based on its appearance. Unfortunately, the answer is that you can&rsquo;t. You really need to look at the information on the bottle and try to identify key components of its production like age, origin, style, still type, and base material. If you can&rsquo;t find this information on the bottle, look it up. The information is out there.</p>
<p>But we still haven&rsquo;t answered the question.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you could only have one rum behind your bar, what would it be?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The most versatile rum, in my humble opinion, is <strong>Plantation 3 Star</strong>. Here&rsquo;s why:</p>
<ol>
<li>Being light in color, you can make clear drinks like the Daiquiri and the Mojito without disrupting the color.</li>
<li>It is from Barbados. Rums from Barbados (and Plantation specifically) tend to be bold, loud, and very &ldquo;rummy.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Despite being a young ish rum, it is still aged in wood barrels and takes on a lot of that flavor. It&rsquo;s young enough that it has a bold flavor, but aged enough that it has mellowed out and calmed down.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a blended rum, so you get the best of both the Coffey still and the Pot still.</li>
</ol>
<p>Plantation 3 Star, on its own, isn&rsquo;t really anything special. It&rsquo;s a decent rum with a very affordable price tag. It&rsquo;s a phenomenal all-rounder that should have a place behind everyone&rsquo;s bar, no matter what you drink. If you&rsquo;re just getting started with rum (shame on you for trying to start with the &ldquo;best&rdquo;), start with Plantation 3 Star. Grab a bottle of Don Q Cristal while you&rsquo;re out. It&rsquo;s a close second for similar reasons.</p>

    <img src="/images/bottles/plantation3star.jpg"  alt="Plantation 3 Star bottle"  class="center"  style="maximum-height: 600px;"  />


]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
